
[
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following tumors (A) ~ (D) is involved in:\nSézary syndrome\nMultiple myeloma\nHodgkin's lymphoma",
    "options": {
      "A": "T-cell tumor",
      "B": "B-cell tumor",
      "C": "Both T and B-cell tumor",
      "D": "Neither"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第1題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following defects (A) ~ (D) affects:\nPurine nucleoside phosphorylase (PNP) deficiency\nIL-4 deficiency\nγc deficiency\nBtk deficiency",
    "options": {
      "A": "T cell development only",
      "B": "B cell development only",
      "C": "Both B and T cell development",
      "D": "Neither B nor T cell development"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第2題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following chemokine receptors is expressed by the activated follicular B cells at the border between the T-cell area and a B-cell follicle in secondary lymphoid tissue?",
    "options": {
      "A": "CCR5",
      "B": "CCR7",
      "C": "CXCR5",
      "D": "CXCR6",
      "E": "CXCR7"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第3題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which deficiency leads to type 2 hyper IgM syndrome (HyperIgM-2)?",
    "options": {
      "A": "AID",
      "B": "Btk",
      "C": "CD40",
      "D": "CD40L",
      "E": "Pax5"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第4題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the followings is NOT the property of TI-1 antigens?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Antibody response in absence of T cells.",
      "B": "Antibody response in infants.",
      "C": "Antibody production in congenitally athymic individual.",
      "D": "Polyclonal B cells activation at high concentration.",
      "E": "Primes T cells."
    },
    "answer": "E",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第5題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Mice have deficiency in MHC I and CD3 molecules:",
    "options": {
      "A": "Both CD4 and CD8 cells mature",
      "B": "Either CD4 or CD8 cells mature",
      "C": "Neither CD4 nor CD8 cells mature",
      "D": "Only CD4 cells mature",
      "E": "Only CD8 cells mature"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第6題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one is not the event during inflammation?",
    "options": {
      "A": "blood clotting",
      "B": "cytokine production by macrophage",
      "C": "extravasation of neutrophils",
      "D": "decrease in vascular diameter"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第1題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one is not a C3 convertase?",
    "options": {
      "A": "C3bBb",
      "B": "C4b2b",
      "C": "C3(H₂O)Bb",
      "D": "C4b2a"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第2題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one is not involved in the innate immunity?",
    "options": {
      "A": "histatins",
      "B": "Toll-like receptors",
      "C": "commensal bacteria",
      "D": "all right above"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第3題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one is not the mechanism for tumor to avoid immune recognition?",
    "options": {
      "A": "apoptosis",
      "B": "antigenic modulation",
      "C": "low immunogenicity",
      "D": "immune suppression"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第4題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one is not the event during inflammation?\nblood clotting",
    "options": {
      "A": "blood clotting",
      "B": "cytokine production by macrophage",
      "C": "extravasation of neutrophils",
      "D": "decrease in vascular diameter"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "explanation": "（D）發炎四大特徵：紅、熱、腫、痛，所以 (D) 應改為 increase in vascular diameter。［出自考古第1題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one is not a C3 convertase?",
    "options": {
      "A": "C3bBb",
      "B": "C4b2b",
      "C": "C3(H₂O)Bb",
      "D": "C4b2a"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "explanation": "(B) 此題在07 是李建國老師的範圍，補體系統中只有 C2 是以a代表大單位，b 代表小單位，而C3 convertase 都是大單位組成，所以沒有C2b。［出自考古第2題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one is not involved in the innate immunity?",
    "options": {
      "A": "histatins",
      "B": "Toll-like receptors",
      "C": "commensal bacteria",
      "D": "all right above"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "explanation": "(A) Antimicrobial peptides 包含 Defensin、Cathelicidins 和 Histatins。\n(B) TLRs 為一種PRR，可以辨識 PAMPs 並引起免疫反應。\n(C) 生物體內的共生菌叢能夠透過競爭，避免外來菌種的入侵。(生物性防禦)［出自考古第3題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one is not the mechanism for tumor to avoid immune recognition?",
    "options": {
      "A": "apoptosis",
      "B": "antigenic modulation",
      "C": "low immunogenicity",
      "D": "immune suppression"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "explanation": "腫瘤藉由下列幾種方式來避免免疫反應：\n(A) Low immunogenicity\n(B) Tumor treated as self antigen\n(C) Antigenic modulation\n(D) Tumor-induced immune suppression\n(E) Tumor-induced privileged sites［出自考古第4題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "配合題:pick up the right answer from the below list\nContact dermatitis\nHay fever\nSteven Johnson syndrome\nSerum sickness\n(inject animal serum)",
    "options": {
      "A": "Type I hypersensitivity",
      "B": "Type II hypersensitivity",
      "C": "Type III hypersensitivity",
      "D": "both Type II and Type III hypersensitivity",
      "E": "Type I, II and III hypersensitivity",
      "F": "Type IV hypersensitivity",
      "G": "all of the Type I, II, III and IV hypersensitivity",
      "H": "none of any type of hypersensitivity"
    },
    "answer": "F",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第1題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "For each of the following select the most appropriate characteristic listed below.\nThe scientist who discovered innate immunity receptor and won Nobel prize",
    "options": {
      "1": "Auto-antibodies to acetylcholine receptor",
      "2": "TH1-cell reaction to thyroid antigens",
      "3": "Autoimmunity due to lack of regulatory T cell activity",
      "4": "T-cell response to neurons",
      "5": "Induced by injection of myelin basic protein plus complete Freund's adjuvant",
      "6": "Auto-antibodies to basement membrane",
      "7": "Auto-antibodies to DNA and DNA-associated protein",
      "8": "Induced by injection of acetylcholine receptors",
      "9": "T-cell response to pancreatic beta cell",
      "10": "anti-bacteria cell wall antibody cross react with cardiac tissue",
      "11": "associated with HLA-B27",
      "12": "Cytotoxic T cell response to thyroid tissues",
      "13": "B. Benacerraf",
      "14": "J. Hoffman",
      "15": "P. Doherty",
      "16": "D. Baltimore",
      "17": "S. Tonegawa"
    },
    "answer": "14",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第2題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "For each of the following select the most appropriate characteristic listed below.\nInflammatory bowel disease",
    "options": {
      "1": "Auto-antibodies to acetylcholine receptor",
      "2": "TH1-cell reaction to thyroid antigens",
      "3": "Autoimmunity due to lack of regulatory T cell activity",
      "4": "T-cell response to neurons",
      "5": "Induced by injection of myelin basic protein plus complete Freund's adjuvant",
      "6": "Auto-antibodies to basement membrane",
      "7": "Auto-antibodies to DNA and DNA-associated protein",
      "8": "Induced by injection of acetylcholine receptors",
      "9": "T-cell response to pancreatic beta cell",
      "10": "anti-bacteria cell wall antibody cross react with cardiac tissue",
      "11": "associated with HLA-B27",
      "12": "Cytotoxic T cell response to thyroid tissues",
      "13": "B. Benacerraf",
      "14": "J. Hoffman",
      "15": "P. Doherty",
      "16": "D. Baltimore",
      "17": "S. Tonegawa"
    },
    "answer": "3",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第2題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "For each of the following select the most appropriate characteristic listed below.\nAnkylosing spondylitis",
    "options": {
      "1": "Auto-antibodies to acetylcholine receptor",
      "2": "TH1-cell reaction to thyroid antigens",
      "3": "Autoimmunity due to lack of regulatory T cell activity",
      "4": "T-cell response to neurons",
      "5": "Induced by injection of myelin basic protein plus complete Freund's adjuvant",
      "6": "Auto-antibodies to basement membrane",
      "7": "Auto-antibodies to DNA and DNA-associated protein",
      "8": "Induced by injection of acetylcholine receptors",
      "9": "T-cell response to pancreatic beta cell",
      "10": "anti-bacteria cell wall antibody cross react with cardiac tissue",
      "11": "associated with HLA-B27",
      "12": "Cytotoxic T cell response to thyroid tissues",
      "13": "B. Benacerraf",
      "14": "J. Hoffman",
      "15": "P. Doherty",
      "16": "D. Baltimore",
      "17": "S. Tonegawa"
    },
    "answer": "11",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第2題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "For each of the following select the most appropriate characteristic listed below.\nExperimental allergic encephalomyelitis (EAE)",
    "options": {
      "1": "Auto-antibodies to acetylcholine receptor",
      "2": "TH1-cell reaction to thyroid antigens",
      "3": "Autoimmunity due to lack of regulatory T cell activity",
      "4": "T-cell response to neurons",
      "5": "Induced by injection of myelin basic protein plus complete Freund's adjuvant",
      "6": "Auto-antibodies to basement membrane",
      "7": "Auto-antibodies to DNA and DNA-associated protein",
      "8": "Induced by injection of acetylcholine receptors",
      "9": "T-cell response to pancreatic beta cell",
      "10": "anti-bacteria cell wall antibody cross react with cardiac tissue",
      "11": "associated with HLA-B27",
      "12": "Cytotoxic T cell response to thyroid tissues",
      "13": "B. Benacerraf",
      "14": "J. Hoffman",
      "15": "P. Doherty",
      "16": "D. Baltimore",
      "17": "S. Tonegawa"
    },
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第2題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "For each of the following select the most appropriate characteristic listed below.\nRheumatic fever",
    "options": {
      "1": "Auto-antibodies to acetylcholine receptor",
      "2": "TH1-cell reaction to thyroid antigens",
      "3": "Autoimmunity due to lack of regulatory T cell activity",
      "4": "T-cell response to neurons",
      "5": "Induced by injection of myelin basic protein plus complete Freund's adjuvant",
      "6": "Auto-antibodies to basement membrane",
      "7": "Auto-antibodies to DNA and DNA-associated protein",
      "8": "Induced by injection of acetylcholine receptors",
      "9": "T-cell response to pancreatic beta cell",
      "10": "anti-bacteria cell wall antibody cross react with cardiac tissue",
      "11": "associated with HLA-B27",
      "12": "Cytotoxic T cell response to thyroid tissues",
      "13": "B. Benacerraf",
      "14": "J. Hoffman",
      "15": "P. Doherty",
      "16": "D. Baltimore",
      "17": "S. Tonegawa"
    },
    "answer": "10",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第2題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "The $T_{H}17$ cells have been demonstrated to play important role on inducing inflammation to rheumatoid arthritis. Which of the following is associated with the development of such T cells in these patients?",
    "options": {
      "A": "IL-2",
      "B": "IL-6",
      "C": "IL-4",
      "D": "IFN-γ",
      "E": "IL-15"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第3題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following molecules is recently found to be associated with severe drug hypersensitivity reaction, Stevens-Johnson syndrome, to anti-seizure drug carbamazepine?",
    "options": {
      "A": "HLA",
      "B": "RORγT",
      "C": "CTLA4",
      "D": "Foxp-3",
      "E": "Interferon gamma (IFN-γ)"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第4題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "IVIG (intravenous immunoglobulin) can be used in the clinics for the treatment of which of the following?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Wiskott-Aldrich syndrome",
      "B": "RAG1/2 deficiency",
      "C": "Isolated IgA Deficiency",
      "D": "Chediak-Higashi Syndrome",
      "E": "Common Variable Immunodeficiency"
    },
    "answer": "E",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第1題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statement about “immunopathogenesis” is correct?",
    "options": {
      "A": "This is the common pathological mechanism induced by immunodeficiency",
      "B": "Pathological mechanisms induced by host immune response against pathogens",
      "C": "Immunodeficiency-induced pathological mechanism without infection",
      "D": "Pathological mechanisms caused by lack of T cells but not B cells",
      "E": "Pathological mechanisms of infection induced only in early childhood"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第2題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "“Hyper-IgM syndrome” can be found in all of the following “except”?",
    "options": {
      "A": "X-linked agammaglobulinemia",
      "B": "Common Variable Immunodeficiency",
      "C": "X-linked Hyper-IgM Syndrome (HIGM1)",
      "D": "Activation Induced Cytidine Deaminase (AID) Deficiency",
      "E": "X-linked Hypohidrotic Ectodermal Dysplasia"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第3題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following immunodeficiency has the first signs of petechiae and bruising? (皮下瘀血)",
    "options": {
      "A": "RAG1/2 deficiency",
      "B": "Wiskott-Aldrich syndrome",
      "C": "IL-7 receptor deficiency",
      "D": "Artemis deficiency",
      "E": "Ataxia-Telangiectasia"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第4題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following about chronic granulomatous disease is correct?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Is a form of graft versus host disease (GvHD)",
      "B": "Is caused by over production of IFN-γ",
      "C": "Can be prevented by irradiation of the recipient before transplantation",
      "D": "Is caused by NADPH oxidase defect",
      "E": "Is caused by polarized $T_{h}2$ response"
    },
    "answer": "A or B",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第5題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Carcinogen induced tumor derived from RAG2(RAG-/-) deficient mouse when transplanted into wild type mouse. (choose the incorrect statement)",
    "options": {
      "A": "Tumors cannot occur due to immunosurveillance",
      "B": "Tumors can be rejected by CD8+ T cell response",
      "C": "Tumors with high immunogenicity can induce anti-tumor immunity",
      "D": "Tumors with low immunogenicity will not be rejected",
      "E": "Tumor developed are less immunogenic"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第6題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statement about “tumor immunoediting” is incorrect?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Tumor can down-regulate the expression of MHC class I molecules",
      "B": "Tumor can down-regulate the expression of TCR molecules in T cells",
      "C": "Tumor can recruit the infiltration of immunosuppressive regulatory T cells",
      "D": "Tumor can secret immunosuppressive cytokines",
      "E": "Tumor can cause T cell apoptosis"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第7題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statement is incorrect?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Tumor cells expressing MHC class I can be killed by CD8+ T cells",
      "B": "Tumors cells with MHC class I down-regulated can be killed by NK cells",
      "C": "Tumor antigens are recognized by NK cells",
      "D": "Tumor antigens can be different in wild-type and nude mice",
      "E": "Nude mice do not have normal adaptive immunity against tumor"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第8題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "The inclusion of GM-CSF in tumor vaccine is to?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Up-regulate MHC molecules in tumor cells",
      "B": "Enhance NK cytotoxic activity",
      "C": "Enhance CD8+ cytotoxic T cell killing activity",
      "D": "Recruit and enhance dendritic cell function",
      "E": "Enhance B cell to produce tumor specific antibody"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第9題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "Herceptin (trastuzumab) is a monoclonal antibody effective in the treatment of?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Colon cancer",
      "B": "Prostate cancer",
      "C": "Head and neck cancer",
      "D": "Non-Hodgkin lymphoma",
      "E": "Breast cancer"
    },
    "answer": "E",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第10題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "(1) 該腫瘤發於T細胞時期。\n(2) 該腫瘤發於B細胞的漿細胞時期。\n(3) 該腫瘤發於B細胞的生發中心(germinal center)B細胞時期。",
    "options": {
      "1": "(1) 該腫瘤發於T細胞時期。",
      "2": "(2) 該腫瘤發於B細胞的漿細胞時期。",
      "3": "(3) 該腫瘤發於B細胞的生發中心(germinal center)B細胞時期。"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第1題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "(1) 該腫瘤發於T細胞時期。\n(2) 該腫瘤發於B細胞的漿細胞時期。\n(3) 該腫瘤發於B細胞的生發中心(germinal center)B細胞時期。",
    "options": {
      "1": "(1) 該腫瘤發於T細胞時期。",
      "2": "(2) 該腫瘤發於B細胞的漿細胞時期。",
      "3": "(3) 該腫瘤發於B細胞的生發中心(germinal center)B細胞時期。"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第2題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "(1) 該腫瘤發於T細胞時期。\n(2) 該腫瘤發於B細胞的漿細胞時期。\n(3) 該腫瘤發於B細胞的生發中心(germinal center)B細胞時期。",
    "options": {
      "1": "(1) 該腫瘤發於T細胞時期。",
      "2": "(2) 該腫瘤發於B細胞的漿細胞時期。",
      "3": "(3) 該腫瘤發於B細胞的生發中心(germinal center)B細胞時期。"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第3題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "(A) AID: Hyper-IgM syndrome type 2\n(B) Btk: Bruton's X-linked agammaglobulinemia\n(C) CD40:Hyper-IgM syndrome type 3\n(D) CD40L: Hyper-IgM syndrome type 1 (X-linked hyper-IgM syndrome)\n(E) Pax5: B-ALL (acute lymphocytic leukemia)",
    "options": {
      "A": "(A) AID: Hyper-IgM syndrome type 2",
      "B": "(B) Btk: Bruton's X-linked agammaglobulinemia",
      "C": "(C) CD40:Hyper-IgM syndrome type 3",
      "D": "(D) CD40L: Hyper-IgM syndrome type 1 (X-linked hyper-IgM syndrome)",
      "E": "(E) Pax5: B-ALL (acute lymphocytic leukemia)"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第4題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "(A) TI-1、TI-2\n(B) TD、TI-1\n(C) TI-1、TI-2\n(D) TI-1\n(E) TD",
    "options": {
      "A": "(A) TI-1、TI-2",
      "B": "(B) TD、TI-1",
      "C": "(C) TI-1、TI-2",
      "D": "(D) TI-1",
      "E": "(E) TD"
    },
    "answer": "E",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第5題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "(A) 因為 B-cell development is arrested at the pre-B-cell stage,所以最多只表現 Pre-B-cell receptor 而無法表現 Immature B cell 之後才有的IgM。\n(B) CVID 介紹見上面 1.(5) 介紹,屬於 B-cell instrinsic hyper-IgM syndrome。\n(C)(D)(E)皆為Hyper-IgM syndrome。",
    "options": {
      "A": "(A) 因為 B-cell development is arrested at the pre-B-cell stage,所以最多只表現 Pre-B-cell receptor 而無法表現 Immature B cell 之後才有的IgM。",
      "B": "(B) CVID 介紹見上面 1.(5) 介紹,屬於 B-cell instrinsic hyper-IgM syndrome。",
      "C": "(C)(D)(E)皆為Hyper-IgM syndrome。"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "explanation": "［出自考古第6題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "配合題:pick up the right answer from the below list\nContact dermatitis",
    "options": {
      "A": "Type I hypersensitivity",
      "B": "Type II hypersensitivity",
      "C": "Type III hypersensitivity",
      "D": "both Type II and Type III hypersensitivity",
      "E": "Type I, II and III hypersensitivity",
      "F": "Type IV hypersensitivity",
      "G": "all of the Type I, II, III and IV hypersensitivity",
      "H": "none of any type of hypersensitivity"
    },
    "answer": "F",
    "explanation": "(1) Type IV hypersensitivity 不是抗體造成，而是由細胞(主要是 $T_{H}$ cell) 造成，稱為 cell-mediated hypersensitivity。以 $T_{H}1$ 為例:接觸性皮膚炎(allergic contact dermatitis)和 tuberculin reaction(結核菌素反應)［出自考古第1題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "配合題:pick up the right answer from the below list\nHay fever",
    "options": {
      "A": "Type I hypersensitivity",
      "B": "Type II hypersensitivity",
      "C": "Type III hypersensitivity",
      "D": "both Type II and Type III hypersensitivity",
      "E": "Type I, II and III hypersensitivity",
      "F": "Type IV hypersensitivity",
      "G": "all of the Type I, II, III and IV hypersensitivity",
      "H": "none of any type of hypersensitivity"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "explanation": "(2) Hay fever(乾草熱)又稱花粉熱，主要由花粉或塵蟎造成，在成人中常見，容易流鼻水、打噴嚏,屬於 Type I hypersensitivity［出自考古第1題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "配合題:pick up the right answer from the below list\nSteven Johnson syndrome",
    "options": {
      "A": "Type I hypersensitivity",
      "B": "Type II hypersensitivity",
      "C": "Type III hypersensitivity",
      "D": "both Type II and Type III hypersensitivity",
      "E": "Type I, II and III hypersensitivity",
      "F": "Type IV hypersensitivity",
      "G": "all of the Type I, II, III and IV hypersensitivity",
      "H": "none of any type of hypersensitivity"
    },
    "answer": "F",
    "explanation": "(3) Stevens-Johnson syndrome 是一個嚴重的皮膚過敏性疾病,臨床上常發生於病人對藥物的過敏反應,嚴重可能致死。先前在東亞人種的研究發現 HLA-B*1502 和對藥物 carbamazepine (CBZ)引起的 Steven-Johnson syndrome 有強烈相關,目前遺傳諮詢或是用藥前同意書都會調查是否帶有 HLA-B*1502的 allele。另外 HLA-B*5801 在歐洲人種的研究中被發現與藥物 allopurinol 有關。屬於 Type IV hypersensitivity［出自考古第1題］"
  },
  {
    "question": "配合題:pick up the right answer from the below list\nSerum sickness\n(inject animal serum)",
    "options": {
      "A": "Type I hypersensitivity",
      "B": "Type II hypersensitivity",
      "C": "Type III hypersensitivity",
      "D": "both Type II and Type III hypersensitivity",
      "E": "Type I, II and III hypersensitivity",
      "F": "Type IV hypersensitivity",
      "G": "all of the Type I, II, III and IV hypersensitivity",
      "H": "none of any type of hypersensitivity"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "explanation": "(4) Type III hypersensitivity 由 IgG 造成,針對 soluble antigen［出自考古第1題］"
  }
]
